A Guide to the American Society of International Law records, ASIL Archives FA1874
Rockefeller Archive Center
American Society of International Law records, ASIL Archives
1900-2006
Rockefeller Archive Center
American Society of International Law
FA1874
4.25 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes, 2 clamshell boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged materials are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Scope and Contents
The American Society of International Law (ASIL) Archives consists of correspondence, newsletters, news clippings, conference material, Tillar House records, and a small selection of research materials pertaining to ASIL history in the institutions centennial.
- Correspondence, 1905-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
- Correspondence, 1911-1915 (Box 1, Folder 11-21)
- Correspondence, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
- Correspondence, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
- Correspondence, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
- Correspondence, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 8-12)
- Correspondence - Subscribers, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
- Correspondence, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
- Correspondence, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 10-13)
- Correspondence, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
- Correspondence, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 16-17, Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
- Correspondence, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
- Correspondence, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 10-14)
- Correspondence, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 15-17)
- Correspondence, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
- American Journal of International Law, 1927-1934 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 9-13)
- Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- ASIL Constitution, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1940-1946 (Box 6, Folder 16-19)
- Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1957-1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Tillar House records - Tillar House Dedication, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Tillar House records - Funds Appeal, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 4-7)
- Tillar House records - Improvements and Furnishings, 1961-1968 (Box 7, Folder 8-12)
- Tillar House records - Butler Room, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Tillar House records, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
- Tillar House records, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1956-1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Manley O. Hudson Medal records, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Bellagio, Italy, Conference Information, c. 1983 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- ASIL Membership Survey and Report, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- ASIL Practice on Taking Official Positions, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
- ASIL Constitution and Regulations, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- 1966 Annual Dinner Transcript, 1966 April (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Photographs, 1900-1950s (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Conferences, 1956-2005 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- SALT, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1965-1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1981-1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- ASIL Newsletters, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- ASIL History - Research Documentation, 2004-2006 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- ASIL History - Photos Considered, 1900-2005 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- ASIL History - ASIL's First Century 1906-2006 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- News Clippings, 1906-1942 (Box 11)
- News Clippings, 1943-1975 (Box 12)